Friends with Brews!
Peter, I am putting an end to 2022 by declaring it to be the year of the megapickle.
What, the actual?
I know that youth isn't ATP, so you should know at least half of it.
But this year, late this year,
John Chidgey resurrected the sound clip of Vic Hudson trying to say megapixel.
To a megapixel.
And then, and then, to make it even funnier, in the very last ATP, here was John Siracusa.
60 megapickles.
It's infectious.
John Siracusa sounds like he was drinking a beer that time. Maybe we should have him on the podcast.
60 megapickles.
I don't think he's a drinker. I really don't.
Let's find out. But I'm a drinker. I admit it.
And more power to him. Okay, now that you've admitted you're drinking, tell us what you're
drinking and why you are drinking. I am about to open up a Golden Road Brewing
Guava Cart. I had noticed that it was exceptionally green, that can. This is the
same company that makes Mango Cart. Are guavas green or are they yellow? I don't
know. I don't either. That can is green and pink. The beer can is green, that's
all you need to know. So yeah. Got it. So this is Guava Cart. It is not a
as sweet as mango cart, but it is 1% higher alcohol than mango cart. So it's a wheat beer.
It's definitely a summery kind of thing. It's made with guava and passion fruit though. So this is a
wheat ale. It's not super sweet, but then again I haven't had it in a few weeks and I've only had
a couple times, so let me take a sip before I review it. It is not sweet at all, but it has a
nice guava flavor to it. And it's got the slightest hint of bitterness at the very end
for only a moment, not unpleasant like most IPAs, for example, and then it's gone.
The slightest hint of bitterness. So that's like me with Google docs. Oh no, no, I'm sorry.
That's extreme rage and bitterness.  Extreme rage and bitterness, right.
Totally the opposite end of the spectrum. On the Tiki scale, you are on this side over here,
Nightmare and this is way closer to best. I love you. So definitely
Why am I drinking this because you said Peter I want to record before Thursday preferably with a beer I was like, oh, okay
I'll drink a beer. So okay. That's why I'm drinking this beer. What are you drinking? Here's my get drunk quick kit
That looks like your daughter's lunchbox or backpack from choosing third grade. This is the only thing I have that's not gigantic
For keeping stuff cool
So it really is her lunch box from when she was in the third grade. No, it's her lunch box from now.
I didn't realize she was in the third grade.
No, this is a space. This is... oh my god. You don't have a girl. Here's what I'm drinking.
Awwww. Peanut butter.
Okay, here's peanut butter milk stout.
Belching beaver peanut butter milk stout.
Okay, that doesn't sound creepy that just sounds foul, but okay.
Yeah, well, it's better than what I put in the show notes because I couldn't remember the belching part
So I put something beaver peanut butter folks doubt. Oh
My god, oh boy, okay, so I thought I had I thought I had I
Thought I had had that on this podcast before but when I used the incredible search tool that I implemented on our website
Which by the way, I really do. I really am glad even if no one else gets any use out of it
I'm so glad I put that on there I use it because I think you and I are probably the biggest users of that because we're
Like wait did I for this already did I did we talk about this? Have I reviewed this? Did I like this?
But when I search for either belching or beaver or belching beaver nothing comes up
So apparently I did not have this on the podcast and by the way, I don't recommend
Only on our website is searching for the word beaver gonna be safe to do
at work
You know, there are probably a lot of park rangers
Dam administrators
Not to be confused with those damn administrators. They're all damn wildlife
Conserved conservationists who probably search for beavers a lot
So while you're pouring that I would like to personally give a shout out to one mr
Vic Hudson and thank him for remembering and reminding you about an app called Shush.
Shush your mouth.
Because thanks to this app called Shush.
You don't know it, but I have had to cough and sneeze twice during this recording and
you have not heard it.
Right.
In the past, Vic, Peter literally had to, he, Peter wears baggy pants.
He had to pull his pants over his head.
Hmm. That's not true. That is not true at all. I had to pull my pants over the microphone.
Oh! That explains some things I saw.
Yeah, so I would wear my old pants back from when I weighed about 200 pounds, so I'd have enough bagginess and I would loosen them up.
I don't believe you ever weighed 200 pounds.
I weighed 212 pounds.
Hey, I got up to 230 at one point in my life.
Yeah, but you're like an inch taller than me, so it's okay.
True. You're right.
Cheers!
Let's not go back there. Cheers. Oh here. That's clink. You need a clinking sound
By the way
This magnetic clip that holds my phone to the top of my macbook pro is why my camera's off to the side
Because my macbook pro sits off to the side of my studio display
But i'm getting a similar thing for
The studio display so eventually I should be able to look you directly in the eyes or you should be able to look me in the eyes
But i'm gonna have to adjust the height on this thing. You could also get a stand for your iphone
Yes, and I have done that in the past and having that extra crap on my desk that I don't want most the time
But no, you want something like a mount it as a mounting for as a webcam. No. No these do mount as a webcam
That's what these do they clip it on to your monitors as a webcam. That's what I mean your phone. No
Yeah, that's what that's what I'm talking about. Oh, so this is your phone. I'm seeing you at yeah
That's exactly that's what I'm talking about. So you could do what I said
What I'm saying is I have on the way a Belkin magnetic mount that will put it on the studio display
Which is in front of me
Excellent, and that way I don't have to use the one that clips it to the laptop which is beside me
Got it. So you're just doing exactly what I said. I'm just not paying any attention to you. You're not paying one
Because I'm drinking. Hey, wait, I said beaver about 20 times to have to go back and
So especially in the Pacific Northwest, I think you have them there. Yeah, no kidding
Has no one heard of OSU, of course every time anybody says OSU they mean Ohio State University
But that is not OSU that is oh, it's also not OSI. Yes you so guava cart versus
Something beaver peanut butter milk stout belting beaver. I what's the what's the alcohol content on that one? Hmm. Good question
Dear listen, I asked pretty much in the dark. It's 12 ounces
5.3 percent. Okay, oh see all of the like the milk stouts and the peanut butter
stouts that I've had are always like super high volume high alcohol by
volume so I would like to try something like that. This is the only peanut butter
milk stout that I've tried that I can endure. Most of them aren't that great
and I don't know why. I've had a couple others hoping I would find something
this is pretty good it's just I will definitely give this a thumbs up but
there's something about it that seems slightly bitter to me kind of like you
in Google Docs and...
Dude, you're the one who was cursing up a storm at Google Docs today.
No, no, I'm extremely bitter, but you must be slightly bitter. Come on. You can't deny it. It is kind of a pain in the ass.
At what, Google Docs?
Yeah, at Google Docing. Google Docs is a pain in the ass at Google Docing.
Honestly, Google Docs has been okay to me. I don't do much with it though, and that's probably why.
Exactly, yeah. Don't use it and you will love it.
Key to every computer technology. It's just like a car. I had it was like I think was my third car
Maybe it was my fourth car. I don't remember third car. I think it was my third car. I had a
Mitsubishi Gallant and
I know as long as I wasn't out there driving it was great
Was it that it was breaking down or it was just constantly?
Constantly and it probably wasn't that much fun to drive either because I don't know what it was about me to be me
It was it was fun to drive. Yeah. Well, it was it was all-wheel drive and it was turbo. It was nice
It was but didn't have a weird interior because there's something about Mitsubishi where early in their ear early in their existence
They set off and said we're just gonna have the weirdest designs you've ever seen. I don't remember that now
This was like 24 years ago though. So it's been it's been a while. So I don't really remember maybe even more
Maybe 25 26 years ago. So now it's even more than that was the early 90s. This was closer to 30 years ago
So I don't remember the interior. What I do remember was the thing was like a rocket sled.
I mean it took off. It didn't accelerate as fast as my Dodge Daytona did.
But it handled a lot better, but it was constantly breaking down.
I don't even remember what was wrong with it.
But there was one quarter where it spent more days in the shop than I had at driving it.
I think it was a Mitsubishi. I think that's what was wrong with it.
That's probably why. I'll drink to that.
What you said there reminded me.
We are at the point in our lives, Peter, where, well at least for me,
anytime I think something happened X number of years ago it's not just ten
years that I have to add to it I have to add at least 20 and there are a couple
things that I have to add 30 years to and that scares the bejeesus belching
beaver right out of the but gel ting but but you the beavers versus yeah the
but gel ting but geever it scares the but gel ting but geever right out of me
That's a pretty good show title too, "The Bejelching Bejever."
"Bejelching Bejever," I like that.
bejeesus.
But I've already got the year of the megapickle.
I think we're good with the year of the megapickle.
I like that.
56 megapickle.
So now that you've talked about Shush app and Vic, you know what's embarrassing is I actually
used to use Shush app, but at some point there was some XLR mic I was using that it just
didn't work on, it just couldn't see the microphone, so I quit using it.
So I kind of forgot all about it.
But I should have known that for a USB mic like yours it would be perfect.
So anyway, my apologies.
It works great for me.
Yeah.
I mean I've used it at least four times.
So I have successfully booked my vacation once again for the second time.
I thought, okay.
Did weSo I'm relocating, I'm relocating to Costa
Rica and I booked two, count them two, Airbnbs.
Right.
Two weeks in one place, two weeks in another place.
But, and why, because, you know, like, well, if I don't like a place, you know, I'm like,
I can probably tough this out for a couple of weeks, but toughing it out for a whole
month, I'm like, I don't, I'm not sure about that.
So I figured I'd split my stay up into two.
The first one canceled on me.
So I was like, huh.
Oh.
So I was like, okay, so I got to find other plans.
And coincidentally, a friend of mine just got back from Costa Rica.
She was there for a week and she used this travel agency to book her hotels and ziplining
and rafting and kayaking and a catamaran tour and other things.
And I was just like, "Alright, that sounds kind of cool."
So I said, "Well, let me check that out."
So I checked it out and I was like, "You know what?
I'm going to do that."
It wasn't really that much more expensive, because now apparently Airbnb prices have
gone up to where they're fairly competitive to, or comparable to hotels.
So hotels are competitive again.
So I was like, well in that case, let me see what's going on.
And this way I've got, someone else cleans the place up, and they include breakfast,
and a driver, and they'll take care of my rental car for me when I'm done.
And so I was like, "What the heck? You know what? Let's let someone else worry about the details."
So I did. So I just booked that this morning.
Interesting. Have you seen pictures of this place? Is it?
Lots of places. They all look the same. Costa Rica is just like lush, lush jungles everywhere.
No, no, no. I'm talking about the hotel.
No, I'll be sleeping out in the jungle.
Oh. Okay.
It's an outdoor hotel.
You have a pillow of bugs.
Very good for your spine.
I don't know what Costa Rica's like, but to me, a lot of hotels are kind of like, eh, whatever.
like they're not the most inspiring. They're feng shui is what I'm trying to say.
Yeah, I wouldn't bet on feng shui in a place like Costa Rica.
So, you know, that's...
So when like when we go to the Oregon coast,
there is a place we like to stay that is like staying in little cottages.
They're usually multi-story, but it's like a little cottage, like a little house.
It's got a real kitchen. It's got real bed. It's like a real house.
As opposed to staying in hotels, because there aren't any hotels that I personally
and joy at all on the Oregon coast that I've found so far.
They're all generic, they're all blah, they, I don't know.
There's just something about staying in them
that just doesn't, it's great if you're never in the room
and you don't care, but if you're gonna spend some time
in there or you wanna eat in there,
or you wanna hang out with your family in there,
no, they're horrible.
And so I'm just wondering if it's gonna be something
like that for you.
And my presumption is you are gonna spend some amount
of time in there since you're there for a month
or two months.
I'm only here for a couple weeks.
A couple weeks in the hotels.
And it's four different hotels over the course of two weeks.
So you know, if I don't like it, I only have to not like it for a couple of days.
So I'm not really...
So basically every other day you're changing rooms?
Every few days.
So yeah.
Every third day.
We'll see.
Yeah, we'll see.
So yeah.
Anyway, so that's that.
That is interesting.
That's kind of a kind of a bummer to be honest.
But I don't want to make you...
No, I don't want to plant that in your head.
Why is that a bummer?
No, it's great.
Because I'm going away on vacation for a month, that's a bummer?
No, I would rather stay in the B&B than the hotel.
Oh, well I've got one for those for two weeks.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yeah, so I'm totally cool with this.
It'll be fun.
Okay.
I figured it's okay.
This way, you know, to get my feet under me, learn a little bit about the culture, etc.,
and have a, you know, a place to...
And you're starting off with that and then you get the presumably nicer place.
Yeah.
Yeah, exactly.
Yeah, that's pretty cool. I'll drink to that here. You can have a beer glass in your camera
What else what else is going on we talked about the shush app again, thanks Vic. Yeah, I wanted to talk about
Some apps that a local Portlander Mario Guzman makes and I'll put links in the show notes
But he basically hates the current state of Apple design
He's a little more extreme than me. He likes everything retro and I I think
current Mac OS is fine except for a few apps. And I will agree the music app is pretty boring and I will agree especially
that the small music widget in the current music app literally seems like a
"We have to have one but who cares and we will never use this ourselves." It's just horrible.
It is not something that a company like Apple should feel at all good about, let alone even just
We'll get back to it later. They should feel shame and regret. So anyway Mario, being a programmer,
has created some music widgets and
when you're using the music app, you can use his music widgets to give yourself a more retro, more beautiful experience and
I have a link to those. You should go take a look at them. They're free. He's not asking for any money.
All he's asking is for you to be able to enjoy your mini widget again.
And if you live in Portland, by the way, he's got the best transit app for Portland. I use it all the time
I introduced it to some people at work and they thought it was the greatest. It's called PDX transit
You can get it for iOS and watch OS and also the Macintosh so you can plan your transit trips
I used it just the other day when I went to the movie theater that I told you all about last time and
or at the time before whenever and
Yeah, it's great. So go to
marioaguzman.github.io and then find him on Mastodon't.
Mastodon't or Mastodon't?
Mastodon't maybe. Find him on Masto maybe.
And tell him that you like him because he's a good guy.
So how's your Mastodon experience? You seem to be enjoying it.
I am. At first I was like, oh, this is going to be painful.
And then I was like, Hey, this is pretty good.
I kind of like this because a whole influx of people are coming.
And now the old time nerds are fighting with the newer people about whether or
not there should be allowed to be quote posts, quote toots.
And there's, I don't know, it's this whole thing where does the platform support it?
No, the platform does not support it.
And it was a choice not to, but third party clients are implementing it.
It's going to happen whether they like it or not.
So what they should probably do is get their asses off their high horses and
their soap boxes and just figure out a better way to implement it for everyone
involved and that'll be consistent. So I can't wait until those people lose the battle. That's
the part of Mastodon that I don't like, but it will go away over time.
Oh, there you go.
But it's still not... Like right now, if I want to know, if I drive out of my driveway
and drive down the street, is my car going to slide off a hill? That kind of stuff is
still not on Mastodon. And I will be amazed if it comes there anytime soon. Do you know
what I'm talking about? Local news accounts, local sources of information that you can
find without even trying on Twitter, that kind of stuff you can't find on Mastodon.
I'm not going to use Twitter just for that. I'm just not going to use Twitter at all right now.
I just don't want to.
You're probably better off not using Twitter. I have looked and I got notifications the other day.
I had to reinstall the IFTTT app on my phone for something. I forget what. I got a notification
that, "Hey, you just posted a new tweet." I still have a recipe so that anytime we post a podcast
or a blog post, it would cross post that over to Twitter. And so I used that as an excuse to
finally learn how to use webhooks in IFTTT and associated that with my Mastodon account.
I don't remember. Is it 25 Ts? It's one F and three Ts, right?
Three Ts, correct. Yes. It's 25 Ts minus 22. Yeah. So I set those up and it wasn't all that hard.
definitely it was harder than just saying connect to Twitter.
Right.
You know, I had to set up an API key and pick the permissions that it had,
but that wasn't all that bad. Now that said,
I don't know if it's actually doing anything yet because I did say...
Because you're not checking.
Well, I told it check and nothing happened,
but sometimes IFTTT doesn't actually check and do anything when you tell it to.
So we'll know when you post the latest episode of friendswithbrews.com.
if that recipe works because should get a note in my Mastodon. And then what I did is it was also set
to post to Twitter. I changed the recipe so it posts to Twitter saying I just posted on Mastodon
but it doesn't actually include the post. So if you want to see what it was, come on over to
Mastodon if Elon will even let you. I actually approve of that because as you know I have
philosophical issues with people who cross route stuff to one platform, but they're never on that
platform. They never engage in that platform. That just seems like a dickish thing to me. It's like,
if you don't want to use that platform, but you're willing to throw stuff at people who still are
there, that just seems jerky. Oh, I take that back. There was one more thing that also auto
feeds into Twitter. Any new post on twitterisgoinggreat.com, I also post that in my
my Twitter feed. Oh, yeah. It's brilliant. Oh my God. Now I have to put the link to Twitter is
going great in here. Oh my God. Peter, that is brilliant. That is genius. I have my moments.
I have my moments. We're friends for a reason. I don't just ignore you all the time on the podcast.
I sometimes I contribute something useful. No, that's hilarious. So the disingenuous thing is
like I saw Ronnie post a mess it on he said that he turned off boosts which are
basically the retweet equivalent because he just doesn't like seeing all the
things that other people boost and I kind of gave him a little grief about
that I was like why would you follow people and then you can't stand what
they're saying like just unfollow the people is my opinion anyway yeah he
turned off boosts which is fine I get look it's an option it's there if he
doesn't like people's boosts he can do that but then later I saw him boosting
someone else's stuff. It's like, okay, now you've gone too far. You don't want to see
boosts from other people. So you've said, but you'll boost, but you'll boost stuff for
other people to have to read. What a hypocrite. I just, I just say it sounds slightly hypocritical.
Yeah. And I love you, Ronnie, but that is a dick move. I'm sorry. Yeah. It's hypocritical
anyway. I don't know if it's a dick move, but it's a hypocritical move. That's for sure.
For sure. It's just easier for me to say dick right now. Cause I've had a bunch of beer
and no food. Well, that'll do that. You know what? I was going to have marionberry Pie
and I forgot to bring it up with me because my wife got me a farm fresh marionberry Pie.
It's not the vegan stuff that we had, but it's just as good. It's non-vegan marionberry
Pie. Non-vegan marionberry Pie. AKA marionberry Pie. Yeah, exactly. Whenever you talk
about that though. I always think about the former mayor of Washington DC.
Wasn't his name Marion Barry? Yeah, but see here...
That's what I always think of when you talk about that.
But in the Pacific Northwest, or at least in Oregon, the marionberry that we think of is
the one that goes in pies and is good. Well, good for you in the Pacific Northwest.
Yeah, if I thought about the mayor when I ate that pie, I wouldn't be so fond of it.
Wasn't he the guy that was in a hotel room with cocaine and he did some things as I recall. Yeah, right. Yeah
So not all marionberries peter
Not only marionberries. Oh dear lord
We know we started a new hashtag
Oh brother
Oh my god. Okay. I love that. So anyway, um, do you want to talk about this eufy thing? Do you care?
Yeah, I do care because I am personally interested in this because Eufy is one of the brands that I was looking at
because I eventually will have to replace my home cameras.
So I have three cameras around the house, some indoor, some outdoor.
And the reason that I bought them is because they, like Eufy, claim to not upload anything to their servers.
But they do integrate either with FTP or Dropbox or I think Google Drive and I have them set to
upload to Dropbox
But the manufacturer
Apparently has now gone out of business
So, oh look you're even more invested than I am
So the manufacturer of my camera is now
apparently gone because the App Store app hasn't been updated in years.
Their website doesn't go anywhere.
Can't buy their product anymore.
And so I'm a little concerned about that.
But, you know, I'm like, they're still working for right now.
But I had been looking at Blink.
I've been looking at Ring.
I'd looked at Nest and I was like,
do I want to give Amazon and Google my cameras?
Not really.
So then there's Eufy.
Now, why might somebody want to go with Eufy and not the ones that I mentioned?
Well, Eufy cameras are pretty convenient.
They work well and they integrate with HomeKit.
A lot of people like Eufy because they're a decent performance for the price.
And as you know, from looking at all your options, home cameras are bloody expensive.
It costs a lot of money to get like even a handful around the house.
So, Eufy, apparently, although they say that they're not uploading stuff to their servers,
they claim that their cameras are local storage only.
But indeed, they have been found to be uploading identifiable footage to the cloud.
And people can even point VLC at it and watch what's happening.
So in theory, I guess it would be possible for other people to get access to it.
But mainly for sure it's going to Eufy.
And Eufy is owned by Anker.
Which you know to be fair I've always liked Anker stuff.
I've got a lot of Anker cables, like Anker chargers.
They're you know as far as I know they're a good brand and as far as I know Eufy is
a good brand.
I've always liked their stuff.
But let's see I think they're talking about how if you know the serial number you can
figure out the address of a camera's feed based on the camera serial number and the
serial numbers aren't super long so they're easy to figure out.
So anyway, the main security threat here is that because they're transmitting stuff and
it's not just local, A, what are they doing with it, and B, other people can also potentially
access it.
Uh-huh.
Yeah, that's a concern.
Anchor initially called it a misunderstanding.
Cough.
Right.
And then basically what they did is started changing their terms of service instead of
actually fixing the problem.
So now their terms of service don't promise as much privacy as they used to.
Hmm. So it's something worth looking at.
I have links in the show notes.
If you have Eufy cameras or you're thinking about Eufy cameras, understand what's happening so that you know whether it's an issue for you or not.
I will say that this issue does not affect anybody who is using them with HomeKit and has the HomeKit secure video feature enabled for those cameras.
Okay. Because that only, all that video gets handled by Apple at that point.
And that's what I do.
So I don't really care about this that much.
What I will do is keep watching to make sure that there are no more occurring
developments that make me think that, okay, this could be a problem for me,
even though I am using homekit, a secure video.
So it's not that I don't care. It's just that as far as I know,
it doesn't affect my use case, but I will continue watching this space for sure.
Watch this space. Yeah. And I don't know, you know, I'm like,
this is a concern because you buy these things thinking that it's going to be
secure. You know,
You think that they're not going to share my data with anyone.
They're not going to share my video with anyone.
Oh, they just did.
And how are you supposed to know until some security researcher finds it out?
Like, well, I mean, you could put a packet capture and sniffer on your network
and just watch it for how long until you gain a level of confidence.
You could also lock it down, firewall the thing down so it can't go anywhere else.
So there's that.
And then you could see, does that break functionality?
and if so, why? What is it doing? Why does it need that access? Yeah, for sure.
Yep. Yep.
That's one of the reasons why whenever people say, "Oh, well, Apple says they don't take
this stuff off device, but they really do." You know, if they did, at some point somebody
would probably figure it out. But it's not like these people went out and bought some
cheap generic Brand X camera and then they were stunned to find out that it was transmitting
stuff to the cloud. No, this is supposedly a good brand that you can trust. They've made
a lot of things, people trust them and then they do this and instead of really responding
in a proper way, they're like, Oh yeah, it's a big misunderstanding. By the way, we're
deleting our terms of service that promise you privacy. Don't look over here.
Yeah. Pay no attention to the man behind the curtain. Yeah. And that's the thing. Like,
so yeah, that is, that's not, that's not the way that you want a company to behave, right?
Right. A lot of times it's not the incident or the thing itself. A lot of times it's more
about how does the company respond. Right. Now to that, and you have recently
gotten on my case to reconsider my password manager.
Well it's just that I, so looking, somebody on Mastodon posted a link to all of the last
past incidents over the past few years and there've been like five or six notable ones
over past several years. I'm talking maybe a six to 10 year span. I don't even remember.
I don't even know how long they've been around.
At one point, they did lose master keys.
They did lose master passwords.
Because unlike 1Password,
1Password doesn't have any access to your master password.
They just don't have it.
That's you.
Only you have that.
And there are some other differences too
with how 1Password does their stuff.
But my main problem with LastPass
is they keep having these little oopses and they keep,
you know, my concerns are more about the company itself.
And then also reading on, as you know,
big security culture there now, following some of those people and reading some of the
things that they've had to say about it. They're not super impressed either with a lot of the
technical things that LastPass is doing, not just its response to this. And so that's why
it was more of my sense that boy, LastPass keeps having stuff happen to them. And I get
the problem with switching when you've got all that stuff in one place, it's super hard
to move it over to another place.
It shouldn't be that hard, I think.
So I've been using LastPass and it's been several years right now.
I only started paying for it a couple of years ago.
So presumably you have a ton of stuff in there.
I do, but it shouldn't be all that hard to just export it out and then import it into
a 1Password or Bitboard.
Those are the two that I'm looking at.
See, I don't know if that's true.
I haven't even looked to see if 1Password has an import.
They claim that they do and they have specific instructions on how to do it from LastPass.
Oh, that's excellent.
Okay.
It's pretty much export and then import.
I figured if they weren't all over that, they should be.
Well, you know, there's 1Password manager that's really, really freaking impossible
to export out and that's the Apple Keychain.
Yes.
That one's a pain to get people to like, so if you want to move to a third party password
manager, ow.
Here's the other problem with Keychain, and this is the reason why I don't use Keychain,
because Keychain has gotten more useful over the years.
As you say, there are some limitations, such as, "How do I get my stuff out?"
Apple once again, once again, Peter, does not understand that some people have families!
And yeah, I guess a lot of those people at Apple do have families, but they don't care,
because they go work 120 hours at a big ring spaceship thingy, and they don't see their
and they don't care what their family does with technology, and when they come home they
just want them to be quiet so they can sit in front of the TV for two hours before they
go to bed and then get up and go back to work again.
Apparently because there is no way to share things with a family member using Apple Keychain.
And I have to have that.
Other than going in and manually, you know, manually decrypt the password, copy it, paste
it and send it to them in an encrypted message?
Right.
And before the 1Password family shared plan, we kind of lived that lifestyle anyway,
Even though we were using 1Password, we would have to send stuff to each other.
1Password had a way of sharing that was supposedly more secure than sharing plain text, but you
know it still isn't what you want to be doing.
But Apple just hasn't come up with something like that.
And I saw, you know, there was one of the Apple employees on Mastodon was like, "Hey,
if you're using LastPass and you don't feel so good about it anymore, here's all the things
Apple Keychain can do."
And I'm like, "Yeah, but it can't understand that I have a wife."
And I never got a response.
But you know, it's like, "Work with me here, dude."
So I guess that's my biggest beef with, I think Keychain is becoming more of a viable
alternative for some people, but like you said, it still has issues getting stuff in
and out.
And then if you have to share it with people, you're totally hosed.
Yeah.
And that's the thing is like, I'd say for plenty of people, it's just fine.
Just use if you just want to use, you know, if you're, it's just you on your Apple devices.
Great, great.
You're fine.
You know, you're, you're good.
You don't need anything fancy.
So there you go.
So talk to me about, well, what's it called?
Megadodo?
Megatrend?
What's the one that you like?
Bitwarden?
Yeah, Bitwarden, whatever.
I just, I don't know, so if I come up with a word, somebody will eventually fill in the
right word.
It's how I...
If I keep spouting out "B*tch" eventually someone will correct me with something accurate.
Fair enough.
I know a lot of people, I work with a lot of people like that.
Well, the difference is I'm not expecting anyone to believe that I think that's what
it is.
I'm just throwing out things until they correct it with the correct one.
Oh, I think most of these people know.
They just just flail and they'll just wait for someone smart to come along and you know,
do that.
I don't know.
I, I, well, yeah, there are though.
Actually.
Yeah, there are those types more often than not.
What I see is the people who want you to think they know what they're talking about.
No, no, no.
I don't see that a lot.
No.
Okay.
So talk to me about bitward.
So, well, no, the, the one thing that it has that 1Password and last pass don't is that
it can be self hosted.
That is the main reason that I'm looking that I'm considering that because I work with certain
organizations that would have that as a requirement.
Oh, okay.
So you could use it essentially like you would say
key pass, except as I understand it,
you can also run a full on server and get all the server
hosted based functionality, just run it on your
infrastructure, not somebody else's.
So that's the only reason I'm looking at that.
Okay, so how would that work?
Would this be like a public facing server?
You could make it that way if you wanted to.
Well, I guess what I'm saying is it's a server
that you can access from anywhere.
Right, well, but that's the thing is some of my clients
might not want it accessible from anywhere.
So they wouldn't do that.
No, but I'm asking how would it actually work?
Well, you would host it on your internal infrastructure
and not host it just anywhere.
So it would only be applicable for,
you could only use it for your work-related stuff at work
or connected to work.
In that example, yes.
I mean, there's nothing stopping me
from spinning up a public instance in AWS
and hosting up there if I wanted to.
Right, but then, so here's the thing
that I always think about.
Look at LastPass.
Now, you are the guy that is responsible
for not being LastPass.
I don't want that burden.
I don't want that burden. Exactly.
That's why I pay 1Password to host the family vaults.
Yeah, yep.
And the minute I find out they're not trustworthy,
I go away.
Yep, but that's the other part too,
is that if Bitwarden was to have a problem
to make you want to leave them, it would have to be in the source code.
Right? So because you're running their stuff, you're not using their infrastructure.
So it'd have to be something wrong with their code that would cause you to leave them,
as opposed to their shoddy practices and their own infrastructure issues that cause you to not like LastPass.
Right. I guess with that, I'd be less worried about Bitwarden software,
and more worried about my ability
to adequately secure a server
that happens to be hosting a password manager.
Yeah, absolutely.
Now on the work network, it would be less of a concern.
You'd still obviously want it as secure as possible,
but if I have to connect to my VPN to get access to that,
that's better than me putting something on a line node
and going, "Hey, you know what?
This'll be great, I'll use this for my passwords.
Only I'm in control of it."
and then some hacker who's scanning ports finds a way out on my server and there's my
Bitwarden stuff.
What could possibly go wrong?
What could possibly go wrong, Peter?
Yeah, that's interesting.
That's a really cool option.
And like you said, for certain circumstances, probably 100% necessary or required.
Good to know.
What are you going to do about your dada?
What's your dada have right now?
He also has LastPass.
We have the LastPass families.
So here's the other thing.
Okay.
to say to me, you know what, I've looked at LastPasswords problems. Okay, there's some
problems, but it is not worth the grief of me trying to get my dad to switch something
else. I would accept that as a completely valid answer, my friend, because what a nightmare
scenario that could be. Here's the thing is though, he doesn't even
know how to use LastPass, so it's fine. How does he get to his passwords?
He doesn't even remember his master password. How does he get to his passwords?
I have the browser automatically fill them in for him.
So it could literally be anything and he wouldn't care.
He has no idea.
As long as some magical thing puts the password in for him.
That magical thing is known as his son.
Okay, but here's the problem.
One password might not be what you want to use then because occasionally 1Password
will ask you for your password.
Occasionally, LastPass does as well.
Usually like if the browser extension gets updated or something and then he'll call me
and say, "I don't remember the password." And since he has, you know, assistants come in and
help him every now and then. So Peter gets in his car and drives from Boston? I don't put his
password on a sticky note that he could, you know, they could also access, which I'm sure if he knew
the password, he would happily just give it to them because he doesn't know who not to trust.
You could call, you could pretend to be anybody and call him and ask for his password. Oh, okay.
Yeah, so anyway, yeah, and I can see now all the social engineering attacks are going to target my father.
By the way, you can locate Peter's dad here. Just kidding. You can't.
So out of all of the users on Strava, I got my year in review.
Well, I'm pretty sure it's not Elon Musk following you because he does not look like a guy who uses Strava.
Drava tells me that I am now in their top 1% of activity.
Are you like the last guy on Strava? Is that what it is?
There are 995 million active users on Strava, so they claim.
So how do you get into the 1%? Did they tell you what that criteria is based upon?
They said by "active," so I would say probably minutes of activity, maybe miles moved, I don't know.
Okay, so I guess what I'm wondering is, are half these people only logging certain events
to Strava and they don't log their every single workout like you do?
Well, what you got to think about is that 1% of 95 million is 950,000.
So I and 950,000 of my closest colleagues are top 1%. So when you look at it in raw numbers,
it's not that impressive because there are a lot of us up there.
But hey, still 1%. Yeah, top 1% on Strava, man.
I don't know what to think about that, Peter.
Lies, damn lies, and statistics.
Right, exactly. I think you should do some research and find out exactly what their criteria is.
Who your competitors for this 1% mark are. Top 1%, that's pretty high.
Well, my competitors are 950,000 other people. That's a lot. You want me to list them all?
Okay. And then there's like 9 billion lazy people on Strava, right?
95 million. Yes. 94 million lazy people. Yes. So yes, there you go. So I'm in the top million
of Strava. Let's just put it that way. Okay. When we say that, it doesn't sound all that impressive.
Well, it does. I don't think I would log daily workouts to Strava. If I would log events,
like if I ever did a century again, or I did any kind of running event, I would log that.
I do like some of the stuff that they use, some of the stuff that they give. Now with the last
iOS update, Apple added a lot more useful data in the Fitness app. But for one thing, it's just
really nice to be able to view it on a big screen on a web browser and not have to stare at my
little phone to try to figure stuff out. Strava lets me more easily import and export stuff.
Strava lets me track stuff that I don't do exclusively with my Apple Watch. Now,
that's not much, but it also does stuff like...
Hey, can you hold that up again tracks your gear that is beautiful. Oh my god. That is the new band
I got to I saw that. Oh my god
Nylon Peter you are more attractive than ever. Well, thank you
One thing that Strava does though is it tracks gear so you can track your shoes and your bikes. Yeah. Yeah
Yeah, you know, it's got some pretty pretty slick
So I'm liking it and I even I pay for it one of the things thoughts right I have to reinstall on my phone
They have an app called Recover. Why are you still paying? You're in the top 1%?
They have an app called Recover, which has rehab and prehab routines. And I realized
I haven't been running that since I wiped my phone out.
They're going to say since you wiped your shoulder out.
No, that's been three years. I know, but I'm telling you, those daily 100 push-ups are not
helping the shoulder, buddy. I'm just here to tell you.
I haven't been doing 100 daily.
You need to listen to Blurring the Lines more often, my friend.
I did, and it sounded like you were just coming to the conclusion finally that maybe you shouldn't
do all those push-ups.
Well, I think that if I was doing them all slowly, well-formed, and listening to my body,
then that they probably wouldn't be hurting, but I definitely have not been doing that.
I don't know if that's a given, because I was very careful about the way I did push-ups,
and I listened to my body.
I would only do as many as I didn't say I have to do X number or I'm gonna die
I said I'll do as many as it feels good and
Still it aggravated my shoulder like crazy. The only push-ups I can do at this point are incline push-ups
I get a very I'm talking 45 degrees at the most
Wall presses if you have to yeah, yeah. Yeah, and and I do other PT exercises, too
Of course, but I'm just saying I don't know what it is about push-ups
But that particular motion when I'm doing planks I can feel that shoulder
And so like if I'm doing a plank and for in yoga, and then you're supposed to lower yourself to the mat and then do your
Cobra or whatever is that what I'm thinking of Cobra chaturanga?
Yeah, I mean if you're doing a classic vinyasa that is anyway when I do that when I lower myself
I don't just lower myself. I can't it will kill my shoulder
I have to let my knees touch before my upper body touches
But that I just know that that particular motion for whatever reason it does a number on the rotator cuff
I wouldn't be too surprised if it does a number on your rotator cuff time will tell we'll find out
Yeah, yeah, because like I was saying on blurring the lines that you know
I haven't been doing a ton of upper body stuff for you know, like even the yoga that I'm practicing
There's not a lot of vinyasa in it. Not a lot of chaturanga
Haven't been doing a lot of boxing not doing any jujitsu now for years
and I'm still feeling, you know, pain.
Although, so yesterday, no day before yesterday,
yesterday I drove to Vermont
to see my parents for Christmas.
The day before, I did three sets of side planks
to mostly work on my low body,
but also works on the shoulders.
So my physical therapist incorporated that into my routine.
My shoulder has not felt better
like in the last couple of years
since after doing just three rounds of side planks.
So whatever that motion was,
that was activating the stuff that I need in my shoulder
to like alleviate all of the discomfort.
So I may switch my daily pushups
to daily side planks instead.
That's not a bad idea.
I will say, I think that part of the reason
that my shoulder got the way it did is that for so long,
I did nothing with upper body, nothing at all.
And then I started trying to do the pushups and I didn't just dive into it
insanely because I was weak to begin with, you know, relatively weak to begin with,
but I probably did too much and,
or I needed to be doing other things besides that in order to keep that from
happening. Yeah.
I just think it was a big mistake to do zero on upper body for all those years.
Well, I'm enjoying the fact that right now my,
my PT exercises,
I think I'm going to be able to turn them into my ongoing strength training
routine. Yeah. So, you know,
I'm planning on doing these couple of times a week maybe. It depends, you know,
depends on, um, you know, what my, my other routine is, but you know,
a little bit of upper body, keep things, you know,
keep things toned and moving and, uh, you know, a lot more lower body. So.
Yeah. I think some of mine I will as well. I think I just need to, it'll,
there'll be some adaptation, right? Like there'll be more resistance for sure.
or there'll be some slight changes,
but the exercises themselves, I think they work pretty well.
Yep.
Well, we should go soon, but before we do,
I wanna play one clip for you, Peter.
Do you know what this is?
I think I can tell by the line in the show notes, yeah.
It's gonna be great.
I think you have sent me some funny stuff lately,
and I thought that we should do a little segment.
Yes, not everything is from John Siracusa, but--
Not everything can be Siracusa says, yeah.
Right, well, I was gonna say,
But those things that are from John Siracusa, those have a special place.
And that special place is Siracusasays.com.
So the nuggets of wisdom that Scott and I deemed to be nuggets of wisdom from
arguably our favorite podcaster, John Siracusa,
go over to our tribute site, Siracusa Says.
We should probably shout out him out, shout him out on Mastodon,
let him know that that site exists.
I thought about that. And then I, you know, he seems pretty easy going.
I've had super minor interactions with him in the past on social networks and but I'm
most afraid to let him know because I don't want him to think we're mocking him and I
don't think it's a fun collection of things John Siracusa has said these are great. They're
great. Okay. Well anyway, did you check the did you check the is is ATP released under
a Creative Commons license or what? I doubt it. I doubt it very much. I wouldn't do that
if I was them. They've got gold there buddy. So he could sue the hell out of us then. Right,
but I have on our FAQ that if at any time in the universe John Siracusa does not feel good
about this, this will stop immediately. Yeah, but that's not going to stop any good lawyer who knows
what the hell they're doing. Why are you doing this? But it says right here, "upon John Siracusa's
request, we will immediately cease and desist, transfer the domain name to him, hand over all
content within, provide him with all source code and assets, and apologize repeatedly
in public and in private.
Jesus, that's pretty extreme.
Well, I'm trying to be a good person here, okay?
But I'm not telling him, so I guess that's not helping in my favor.
Okay.
Anyway, let me play...
So if anybody has never heard the episode of...
Was it ATP that had the windows of Siracusa County?
I think that was ATP.
Go find the windows of Siracusa County on ATP.
It is a treasure.
It is the most beautiful thing you will listen to.
And then re-listen to this clip that I'm about to play.
This is from… what's it called?
Grumpy Geeks?
Or something like that?
What's it called?
Grumpy Old Geeks.
Okay.
Grumpy Old Geeks podcast.
"I reopened Edge and clicked on the restore button that's part of Edge, but Edge crashes
and closes again after a minute of trying to restore my 1600 open tabs."
You're doing it wrong, buddy.
You're doing it wrong.
I don't think you understand internet.
No, you don't know how the f*** to use the internet.
Have you heard of bookmark?
Nope.
They just keep opening tabs.
It's like when I see somebody's phone and they have like 8,000 unread emails and I just
want to tear my skin off my face.
Oh, I've seen them over 100,000.
I've seen them over 100,000 unread messages in an email and I'm just like, "Oh my God."
Have the decency to turn off the number on your icon, sir.
I'm just like, how dirty are your private parts?
You have to be a filthy human being if you can't get rid of your emails.
I agree with everything they said.
See now like John Siracusa's use case would drive me insane.
I am more like John Siracusa than I'm like Marco and Casey.
I don't close stuff all the time.
I leave stuff open for long periods of time and I go back to it.
But I'm way more on the end of the spectrum approaching them than I am on the end of the
spectrum approaching zone.
John Siracusa who has billions of windows open, each with their own amazing set of tabs,
terminal windows open and somehow he just thinks that in his brain he's gonna know how
to find that instantly and that he's more efficient that way.
1600 tabs.
I will put a link in the show notes for the windows of Siracusa County.
You have to.
That's all I'm gonna say.
Another good episode.
Yes.
Well on that note, I think we should wrap up this show.
What do you think?
I think so.
But before we do that, shouldn't we tell people where to find us?
Yeah, we should tell people where to find us, Peter.
Well you can find me.
The easiest way is on nikolaidis.com.
And then from there, you've got links to all of the things,
including my Mastodon account.
You can find me at scottwillsey.com.
I don't know if there's links to everything on there,
but there's a link to my Mastodon.
Also, as you know, if you're listening to this,
you might know that there's friendswithbrews.com.
You also might know now, because we talked about it,
that there's siracusasays.com.
And yeah, you can find us,
and you can search for beers on our website.
Please use the search function and search for "Belching Beaver."
It'll be there by the time you listen to this.
There you go.
All right, Peter, hit your big red button.